History of Photography Collection
Yale University Arts Library
History of Photography Collection
1900-2005
VRC 65
Yale University Arts Library
2.91
7 boxes
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of artistic photographs. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of artistic photographs. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged alphabetically by country. Further arranged by individual artist name.
Photography; Photography -- History; Photographs; Reproductions
- General photography (Box 1)
  General
  [8 photographs]
- Miscellaneous countries (Box 1)
  [19 photographs]
  Includes three folders of miscellaneous clippings
- Unknown countries (Box 1)
  - Morimura, Yasumasa, 20th century [1 photograph] (Box 1)
  - Shonibare, Yinka, 20th century [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Australia (Box 1)
  - Billington, Robert [1 photograph] (Box 1)
  - Lindt, John William, 1845-1926. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Austria (Box 1)
  - Haas, Ernest, 1921-1986. [2 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Kuhn, Heinrich, 1866-1944. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Belgium (Box 1)
  - Magritte, Rene, 1898-1967. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Brazil (Box 1)
  - Ferrez, Marc, 1843-1923. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Cuba (Box 1)
  - Mendieta, Ana, 1948-1985. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Holland (Box 1)
  - Andriesse, Emmy, 1914-1953. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Italy (Box 1)
  - Bragaglia, Anton Giulio, c. 1890-1960. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Japan (Box 1)
  - Unknown artist [1 photograph] (Box 1)
  - Kusakabe, Kimbei [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Lebanon (Box 1)
  - Hatoum, Mona, 1952-. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Norway (Box 1)
  - Munch, Edvard, 1863-1944. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Spain (Box 1)
  - Unknown artists [1 photograph] (Box 1)
- Switzerland (Box 1)
  - Bischof, Werner, 1916-1954. [2 photographs] (Box 1)
- Britain (Box 1)
  - Unknown Artists [42 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists (Box 1)
    - Annan, J. Craig, 1864-1946. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Annan, Thomas, 1829-1887. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Barkshire, Paul, 1953-. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Billingham, Richard, 1970-. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Bourne, Samuel, 1834-1912. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Bown, Jane [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Brandt, Bill, 1904-1983. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Dixon, Henry, 1820-1893. [2 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Emerson, Peter Henry, 1856-1936. [2 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Evans, Frederick H., 1853-1943. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Frith, Francis, 1822-1898. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Godwin, Fay, 1931-2005. [4 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Hamilton, David, 1933-. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Hockney, David, 1937- .[2 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Kilip, Christ, 1946-. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - McCullin, Donald, 1935-. [4 photographs] (Box 1)
    - McKenzie, Joseph [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Newby, Eric [2 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Parkinson, Norman, 1913-1980. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Piper, John, 1903-1992. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Riley Brothers [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Robinson, Henry Peach, 1830-1901. [3 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Thomson, John, 1837-1921. [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Tress, Arthur [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Webb, Boyd, 1947- [1 photograph] (Box 1)
  - Individual Artists [50 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Beaton, Cecil, 1904-1980. [3 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Brandt, Bill, 1904-1983. [5 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Cameron, Julia Margaret, 1815-1878. [16 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Hill, David Octavius, 1802-1870. [9 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830-1904. [4 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Sutcliffe, Frank M., 1853-1941. [4 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Talbot, William Henry Fox, 1800-1877. [9 photographs] (Box 2)
- Canada (Box 2)
  - Known artists. [16 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Karsh, Yousef. 1908-2002. [14 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Notman, William, 1826-1891. [2 photographs] (Box 2)
- France (Box 2)
  - Unknown artists. [3 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Known artists. [54 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous artists (Box 2)
    - Aguado, Onesipe, 1831-1893. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Baldus, Edouard Denis, 1813-1882. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Boubat, Edouard [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Brassaï (Gyula Halasz), 1899-1984.[2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Carone, Walter [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Clergue, Lucien, 1934-. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Courtellemont, Gervais [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Davanne, Louis Alphonse, 1824-1912. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Doisneau, Robert [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Durieu, Eugene, 1800-1874. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Hausmann, Raoul, 1886-1971. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Kollar, François, 1904-1979. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Langerock, Henri, active ca. 1860-1879. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Lartigue, Jacques-Henri, 1896-1986. [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Lumière, Auguste, 1862-1954. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Mounicq, Jean [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Nadar, Felix, 1820-1910. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Niepce, Nicephore, 1765-1833. ]1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Pierson, Louis [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Rault, Jean, 1949-. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Rheims, Bettina, 1952-. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Riboud, Marc, 1923-. [3 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Tabard, Maurice, 1897-1984. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Vasson, Jenny de [1 photograph] (Box 2)
  - Individual artists (Box 2)
    - Atget, Eugene, 1857-1927. [9 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Braun, Adolphe, 1811-1877. [7 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henry, 1908-2004. [9 photographs] (Box 2)
- Germany (Box 2)
  - Known artists. [37 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous artists (Box 2)
    - Bayer, Herbert, 1900-1986. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Becher, Bernd and Hilla [4 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Biermann, Aenne, 1898-1933. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Gursky, Andreas [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Held, Louis,1851-1927. [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Henle, Fritz, 1909-1993. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Hesse, Martin [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Hoffmann, Heinrich, 1885-1957. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Kesting, Edmund, 1892-1970. [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Lebeck, Robert, 1929-. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Lehndorff and Trulzschn [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Moholy, Lucia, 1899-1989. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Renger-Patzsch, Albert, 1897-1966. [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Rosswog, Martin, 1950-. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Zille, Heinrich, 1858-1929. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
  - Individual artists (Box 2)
    - Bellmer, Hans, 1902-1975. [7 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Sander, August, 1876-1964. [8 photographs] (Box 3)
- Hungary (Box 3)
  - Moholy-Nagy, Lazslo, 1895-1946. [4 photographs] (Box 3)
- Mexico (Box 3)
  - Modotti, Tina, 1896-1942. [9 photographs] (Box 3)
- Russia (Box 3)
  - Alpert, Max [1 photograph] (Box 3)
  - Chegin, Andrey [1 photograph] (Box 3)
  - Kozhemyakin, Sergey [1 photograph] (Box 3)
  - Rodchenko, Alexander [8 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Shakhet, Arkady [1 photograph] (Box 3)
- Unites States (Box 3)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings
  - Unknown artists (Box 3)
    [12 photographs]
  - Known artists (Box 3)
    - A - Miscellaneous Artists [72 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991. [2 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Abell, Sam [2 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Adams, Robert [1 photograph] (Box 3)
    - Adelman, Bob [1 photograph] (Box 3)
    - Albers, Joseph, 1888-1976 [1 photograph] (Box 3)
    - Arbus, Diane, 1923-1971. [3 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Arnold, Eve [2 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984. [54 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Austen, Alice, 1866-1952. [6 photographs] (Box 4)
    - B - Miscellaneous Artists [27 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Babis, Larry [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Ball, J.P., 1825-1901. [3 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Barrow, Thomas, 1938- [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Bell, Charles M., 1848-1893 [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Berko, Ferenc, 1916-2000. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Bing, Ilse, 1899-1998 [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Bodine, A. Aubrey, 1906-1970 [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Bown, Jane [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Brady, Mathew B., 1823-1896. [3 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Brown, Dean, 1936-1973. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Bubriski, Kevin [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Bullock, John, 1854-1939. [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Bullock, Wynn, 1902-1975. [3 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Burson, Nancy, 1948-. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - C - Miscellaneous Artists [29 photographs.] (Box 4)
    - Callahan, Harry, 1912-1999. [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Capa, Cornell, 1918-. [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Capa, Robert, 1913-1954. [4 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Catledge, Oraien E. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Chamlee, Paula, 1944-. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Clark, Larry, 1943-. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Clift, William, 1949-. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Coburn, Alvin L., 1882-1966 [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Conniff, Gregory [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Croner, Ted [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Cunningham, Imogen, 1883-1976 [4 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1976. [4 photographs] (Box 4)
    - D, E, F - Miscellaneous Artists [60 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Dater, Judy, 1941- [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Davidson, Bruce [3 photographs] (Box 4)
    - DeCarava, Roy, 1919-. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - DeMeyer, Baron Adolf, 1868-1949. [3 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Depardon, Raymond [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Dexter, King [2 photograph] (Box 4)
    - DiCorcia, Philip-Lorca [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Disfarmer, Mike (Meyer), 1884-1959. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Dixon, Joseph Kossuth [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Doolittle, James N.[1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Easterly, Thomas M., 1809-1882. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Erwitt, Elliot, 1928-. [4 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Fauree, Louis, 1916-. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Fink, Larry [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Fitz, Henry, active 1839. [1 photograph] (Box 4)
    - Freed, Leonard, 1929-2006. [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Friedlander, Lee, 1934-. [4 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Frissell, Toni, 1907-1988. [2 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Eakins, Thomas, 1844-1916. [9 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1898-1995. [6 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Evans, Waler, 1903-1975. [10 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Feininger, Andreas, 1906-1999. [3 photographs] (Box 5)
    - G, H, I.- Miscellanoeus Artitsts [27 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Gardner, Alexander [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Gaskell, Anna [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Gaskell, Anna [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Gilpin, Laura, 1891-1979. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Gittleman, Len, 1932-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Groover, Jan, 1943-. [3 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Gutmann, John, 1905-1998. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Harper, Alvan S., 1847-1911. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Harris, Alex, 1949-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Hester, Wilhelm, 1893-c.1920. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Hillers, John, K. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Horst, Horst P., 1906-1999. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Imes, Birney, 1951-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Hine, Lewis, 1874-1940. [6 photographs] (Box 5)
    - J, K, L - Miscellaneous Artists [67 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Jackson, William Henry, 1843-1942. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Johnston, F. B., 1864-1952. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Kanfer, Larry, 1956- .[2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Kasebier, Gertrude [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Kasten, Barbara [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Klein, William [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Klett, Mark, 1952-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Kumler, Kipton, 1940- .[2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lanker, Brian [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lavenson, Alma, 1897-1989. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lawler, Louise [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Lazar, Arthur, 1940-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Lee, Russell, 1903-1986. [3 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Leipzig, Arthur, 1918-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Leonard, Herman, 1923-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Levitt, Helen [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Light, Ken [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lion, Jules, c.1810-1866. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lipper, Susan [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lynes, George Platt, 1907- [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Kertesz, Andre, 1894-1985. [9 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Kruger, Barbara, 1945-. [9 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Lange, Dorothea, 1895-1965 [10 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Laughlin, Clarence John [6 photographs] (Box 5)
    - M - Miscellaneous Artists [44 photographs] (Box 5)
    - MacKichan, Margaret A., 1948-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Mann, Sally [3 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Mark, Mary Ellen, 1941-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Matta-Clark, Gordon, 1943-1978. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Matteson, Sumner W., 1867-1920. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - McGowan, Kenneth [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - McWilliams, John IV, 1941-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Mertin, Roger, 1942-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Metzner, Sheila [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Meyerowitz, Joel, 1938-. [2 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Mili, Gjon [ 1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Miller, Ken, 1963-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Misrach, Richard, 1949-. [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Mortenson, Ray [1 photograph] (Box 5)
    - Man Ray, 1890-1976. [16 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Mapplethorpe, Robert, 1947-1989. [8 photographs] (Box 6)
    - N, O, P - Miscellaneous Artists [33 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Nagatini, Patrick, 1945-. [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - NASA, Apollo 8 mission. [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Nauman, Bruce, 1941-. [2 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Newman, Arnold, 1918-. [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Nixon, Nicholas, 1947-. [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Noggle, Anne [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - O'Sullivan, Timothy, 1840-1882. [7 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Parker, Bart, 1934- [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Parker, Olivia [2 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Parks, Gordon, 1912-2006 [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Partridge, Ronald 1917- [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Pfahl, John [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Plowden, David, 1932- [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Plumbe, John, 1809-1857 [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Porter, Eliot, 1901-1990 [2 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Penn, Irving, 1917- [9 photographs] (Box 6)
    - R, S - Miscellaneous Artists [73 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Rankin, Tom [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Raymond, Lilo, 1922- [2 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Rosenblum, Walter, 1919- [2 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Russell, Andrew J., 1936- [4 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Serrano, Andres, 1942- [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Sexton, John [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Sipprell, Clara, 1880-1975 [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Siskind, Aaron [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Smith, Edwin [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Spano, Michael [2 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Starn Twins [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Sternfeld, Joel [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Stettner, Louis [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Strand, Paul, 1914-1976 [3 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Stuler, Jack, 1932- [1 photograph] (Box 6)
    - Riis, Jacob A. [3 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Shahn, Ben, 1898-1969 [4 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Sheeler, Charles, 1883-1965 [7 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Sherman, Cindy, 1954- [9 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Southworth, Albert [7 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973 [6 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946 [6 photographs] (Box 7)
    - T, U, V - Miscellaneous Artists [22 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Tenneson, Joyce [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Tice, George A., 1938- [3 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Trager, Philip [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Turner, Pete, 1934- [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Ubac, Raoul, 1910-1985 [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Uelsmann, Jerry, 1934- [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Ulmann, Doris, 1884-1937 [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Uzzle, Burk [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Van Cleef, June, 1941- [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Van der Zee, James, 1886-1983 [4 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Vroman, Adam Clark [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - W, X, Y, Z - Miscellaneous Artists [33 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Wall, Jeff [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Watkins, Carleton E., 1825-1916 [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Weegee, 1899-1968 [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Wegman, William, 1943- [4 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Weiner, Dan, 1919-1959 [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Welsch, Ulrike [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Weston, Brett, 1911-1993 [3 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Weston, Cole, 1919-2003 [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - White, Minor [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Winogrand, Garry [2 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Witkin, Joel Peter [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Wright, Holly [1 photograph] (Box 7)
    - Weston, Edward, 1886-1958 [12 photographs] (Box 7)